odmp.org 2019-12-09

# Privacy Statement

The Officer Down Memorial Page, Inc., (ODMP) is strongly committed to protecting the privacy of its online visitors. Personally identifiable information about individuals is not collected, except when it is knowingly provided by such individuals. The terms of this privacy policy shall govern all interactions with the Officer Down Memorial Page, Inc., either through the ODMP website or e-mail. A link to this privacy policy can be found on most pages throughout the ODMP website. By using the ODMP website or communicating with the ODMP by e-mail, you agree to the terms of this policy.

#### INFORMATION PROVIDED BY VISITORS

The Officer Down Memorial Page website can be used without registering or submitting any personal information. However, in order to gain access to certain features of the site and the ODMP e-mail newsletters, you will be required to register.

If you decide to register, you may be required to provide personal information that may include a username and password, your name, e-mail address, postal address, and telephone number. We store all information provided, along with your other preferences, on our secure server(s).

#### INFORMATION AUTOMATICALLY COLLECTED

The Officer Down Memorial Page, Inc., utilizes cookies to collect non-personal information when you request pages through your browser. Cookies are used to collect aggregate information for site traffic analysis, such as the number of visitors and the number of pages viewed. The information collected helps the ODMP monitor how visitors use the site, allowing us to tailor the design to visitors' needs and preferences. The website has been designed to provide nearly full functionality without cookies, but some features will not be available without cookies. Refer to your web browser's instructions if you desire to reject the cookies.

Cookies for registered users allow you immediate access to certain features on the website. These cookies include a session identifier that we can map to your personal information on our secure server. Your personal information will never be transmitted across the Internet from the website, except when you initially submit it or modify it.

#### E-MAIL COMMUNICATION

The Officer Down Memorial Page, Inc., regularly sends newsletters and special announcements to registered users. Registered users may subscribe or unsubscribe to the ODMP mailing lists at any time.

#### SHARING OF INFORMATION

Personal information collected by the Officer Down Memorial Page, Inc., is never shared with third-party organizations except as defined in this section. In certain circumstances, memorial and personally identifying information collected by the ODMP may be shared with the National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial Fund, Inc., or Concerns of Police Survivors, Inc. This sharing of information will only take place in the event that direct action is needed for those organizations to begin their process of honoring fallen law enforcement officers.

In situations involving threats against law enforcement officers, all information collected about the individual who transmitted the threat will be provided to the appropriate law enforcement agency for investigation.  Any activity which is suspected of being in violation of United States federal or state law may be reported, along with personally identifying information, to appropriate law enforcement agencies.

#### EUROPEAN UNION GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR)

No personal information should be submitted by any citizen of the EU. E.g., EU citizens are not permitted to create accounts, and EU citizens are not permitted to submit Reflections that contain any personal information. Any existing accounts or Reflection data that ODMP knows belonging to EU citizens will be deleted prior to May 25th, 2018. Citizens of the EU who previously left a Reflection or created an ODMP account may request that their data be deleted in compliance with GDPR by using our contact form and submitting a request in writing.  

#### REVISIONS

The Officer Down Memorial Page, Inc., may revise this Privacy Policy at any time. You are encouraged to visit this page periodically to review our current policy.

Rev. 5/16/2018
